Now, that brings me neatly
to point 16:
there is still a great deal
of noise going on at night.
Laughing, giggling, horseplay.
Now, we all get bored, that's
inevitable in our circumstances,
but may I remind you,
we are at war. I w...
Ah, Lieutenant.
Communiqué for you, sir,
from HQ. Marked urgent.
Ah, finally.
This would be my requisition
for a service revolver.
(clears throat)
(mutters indistinctly)
Good God.
Sir?
France has surrendered.
My God, they've taken France.
(murmuring)
The Germans are coming.
I don't think they'll
be here just yet, sir.
What? Right.
May I suggest we initiate
the emergency
lockdown protocol, sir?
Yes. Yes.
Jolly good.
It's vital that nothing
fall into enemy hands.
You heard the C.O.
Get to your duties.
Sir.
(quiet chatter)
Eh, exciting times, Havers.
If they do invade, we may get
a proper pop at Jerry.
Yes.
About that, sir...
I know we do
vital work here, sir,
but I want to get involved
in the fighting.
I've put in
for a transfer.
You're leaving?
There's talk
of a North Africa front.
Yes.
Yes, well,
I-I-I totally understand.
Of course.
(chuckles)
Carry on.
Thank you.
♪ ♪
PAT: And seeing as nobody else
has volunteered, I thought
this evening, before film club,
I would give you all
a little talk
on activity badges.
(all groan)
-So...
-OTHERS: There are 37 badges
that you can collect.
-Badge number one, bivouacs.
-PAT: All right.
Well, I'm sorry,
I mean... (scoffs)
...if anyone has anything new
that they'd like to, uh...
(stammers) I could do,
uh, my talk
on how to, uh, skin a mammoth.
You start at the...
(both groan)
That's not new.
That's not strictly new, is it?
(overlapping arguing)
I'm ready to talk
about the witch trial.
Witch trial.
If-if-if it be of interest?
PAT:
Oh, Mary,
I mean, if you feel like
you're ready.
MARY: Well,
I knows it-it's
taken me a whiles
to-to talk.
Only about
300 years.
But, yeah, I-I think
I-I'm ready.
And how many rooms
do you have?
Oh, I think
there's, like...
Hmm...
Natural light,
so that's a... Mm.
Ooh, period stairs,
clearly.
(chuckles)
Hmm.
Interesting space.
Sort of rustic.
Colonial.
Quite a niche market,
wedding-wise.
I heard Isabelle
from Belle's Weddings passed,
and you were sick on her.
Uh, no, I was sick near her.
Can I be honest with you?
I don't like it.
I love it!
It is a little shabby
around the edges,
but with a bit of zhuzhing up,
this could really suit
the right couple.
Uh, and do you happen
to have any clients
who are interested,
like, soon? (chuckles)
Soon?
MARTIN:
There is one,
Clare. I'm showing her
some other places today.
She wants
to book in ASAP.
Shotgun wedding.
(chuckles)
I'm kidding.
I think this could work
for them.
Piano, tick.
Open fireplace, tick.
Canape room, tick.
Move painting
of creepy old lady, tick.
Kitchen, tick.
Perfectly placed
to allow you to flow
right through this corridor
straight into your garden
at the back,
where you can set up
your main marquee
right... here.
Oh, no.
Uh, yeah.
We can't
show people this.
There's rough around the edges,
then there's a bomb site.
We haven't quite got around
to clearing it yet,
but we will.
By this afternoon?
When?
What?
I was going to
bring Clare around
after showing her
the other venues,
but I can't
show her this.
You have to make space
for this sort of marquee
if you want
to host weddings here.
Without it,
you've no catering flow.
No flow, no go.
Yeah.
Mm.
Guys,
you've got to get it
wedding ready.
We'll clear it.
We will?
Is what I wanted to hear.
(both chuckle)
Let's make this happen.
I'll delay Clare
as long as I can,
say 4:00?
Ciao, ciao.
MIKE:
Five hours.
Loads of time.
PAT:
So, film club, now,
I know it's not my turn
to choose, but I
would like to lobby hard
for Top Gun.
Not again.
I don't know about you,
Mary, but, uh,
I quite like the look of, uh,
ooh, Chariots of Fire.
(grunts softly)
No, actually, uh, how about
Mississippi Burning?
(chuckles)
Towering Inferno?
Hmm.
Huh.
Maybe she is ready.
JULIAN: Huh.
Could be the case.
Anyway,
it's my turn
to choose this week,
so, tish, tish, tish.
I don't think so,
mate. It's mine.
Faradiddle, sir.
You had your turn two weeks ago.
You swapped with me.
No, no. I don't recall to
that, and even if I did,
it would have been
a verbal, nonbinding
agreement.
You show me your thumb, sir.
I would show you my glove,
sir, if I had one.
And I would give you
a bunch of fives, mate.
I used to box for
Cambridge, you know.
Let's go. Let's go,
pal. Oh, yes.
Guys, guys, guys,
s'il vous plait.
French.
Ooh.
Why don't we put it to the vote?
Oh, yeah, put it to the people.
Like they know
what they're doing. (scoffs)
Hands up who thinks
it's Thomas's turn?
I've got my hand up,
probably. Somewhere.
Uh, ra-da-da-da-da.
Hang on, not everyone's here.
Well, where are they?
ALISON:
Oh...
my... God.
Oh, Martin's right, we're
never gonna be wedding ready.
Well, let's get redding wed--
ready ready. Uh... wed...
(ghosts arguing)
Oh, no.
Alison, if you please.
Julian says that it's his turn
to choose for film club,
but it isn't,
it's mine.
Please, everyone,
we-we're having
a bit of a crisis here.
This is a crisis.
You know. I mean...
(overlapping arguing)
Okay, guys, guys, guys...
Shut up, okay?!
Let her speak. Sorry.
You can speak.
We're trying to get
this wedding booking.
Oh, there's going to be
a wedding.
How wonderful.
The dresses, the men,
the kissing. (chuckles)
ALISON:
We need to clear
this whole garden
by 4:00. We're never
gonna do it.
Hang on a minute.
Oh, jinx. You go first, Michael.
We can do it.
If we clear that... Hmm...
And then we move this...
(gasps) And I'll help, too.
How, Pat?
I could be your wingman.
You know, like in Top Gun.
I can be Goose
to your Maverick, yeah.
I'd keep this lot occupied while
you do what you have to do,
and Goose dies in the film,
so, you know, works out,
doesn't it?
Thanks, Pat.
PAT: Yeah.
MIKE:
Yeah, of course
we can fit a marquee in.
Like, how hard can it be?
They put a man on the moon.
What? What? What'd he say?
D...
Uh...
Man on moon-ah?
MIKE:
Okay, I'll go get the tools.
You check the measurements.
Let's get redding red...
Wedding ready.
Wedding...
Let's get wedry...
It's wedding ready.
Let's do this. Yes!
MARY:
Alison,
what was the man doing
up there on the moon?
They went to explore.
Oh.
THOMAS: And how
did he get there?
Climb up a beanstalk,
did he?
ROBIN:
I don't believe it.
No. No.
There's no way
it could happen.
Pat, now would be a really good
moment to be a wingman.
Great. Okay, everyone,
let's turn and burn.
Oh, sorry, Mary.
It's a quote from Top Gun.
PAT:
Think about it, Robin.
Man has always
looked up
at the moon and thought...
Can you eat it?
No, can you walk on it?
Press play.
(music playing over video)
NARRATOR (over video):
In 1969,
the world watched in wonder...
Thanks, Pat.
...as three brave astronauts
took off from Cape Canaveral.
Their destination: the moon.
ROBIN: Ooh.
PAT: It's an amazing moment.
Everyone remembers
where they were.
I was with Carole,
at her parents'.
JULIAN:
I missed the whole thing.
I was still a student
at Cambridge.
Busy having my own
moon landing,
if you know
what I mean.
My first threeso...
Moon-ah.
CAPTAIN:
Ah, there you are.
What's going on here?
Oh.
I'm helping Alison, yes.
Keeping this lot busy while
she and Mike dig up the garden.
Which garden?
How you getting on?
It's gonna be a squeeze. First,
we have to clear
all of this.
CAPTAIN:
No! No.
Belay that order, Michael.
You can't dig there.
That's a negative.
Wait, sorry. One second, Mike.
Didn't you tell
them we're busy?
Most of them are
watching YouTube.
Jel.
Why can't we dig there?
Because that's a very special
part of the garden.
Uh, that was where our allotment
was, the regimental allotment.
Okay, it's fine, Mike,
you can just keep digging.
Uh, no, th-that's where
we buried our pets.
Um, uh, my dog
is buried there.
Right there, and
he was very special to me.
Barry. Barry? Barry.
Wait, Mike. (sighs)
So, sorry, you had a dog
called Barry?
Mm-hmm.
Okay. Mike, you can
just carry on.
No, thank you, Michael. Ow.
Oh, that was a deep one.
(groans)
Call him off. Call him
off, I tell you.
Okay. Wait just
one second, Mike.
When I was at Button House,
there was a war on.
I don't think that's
ever come up before.
There is something buried down
there that is very sensitive.
Captain, the war is over.
Please.
Don't dig.
There's something down there
that is potentially explosive
if it gets out.
Uh... Mike, do you think we
can clear the other side?
Just the other side, Michael.
(scoffs) Looks like
a lot of work.
Sorry, it's a ghost thing.
Well...
Yeah.
(whistle blows in distance)
(officers shouting commands)
(knock on door)
Come.
Ah, Havers.
Yeah, at ease, at ease.
I was just
thinking about you, actually.
How is the emergency
lockdown coming?
Very good, sir.
Most items have been
squared away, as per the order.
Excellent.
BOTH:
I've come to tell you that...
Sorry, you first,
Lieutenant.
(chuckles)
I'm afraid I'm leaving you, sir.
At 1800 hours this evening.
So soon.
Of course. Yes.
It's North Africa,
sir.
I'll be able to have
a proper swing at Fritz.
You make sure you give him
a bloody nose.
I shall miss you, Havers.
(stammers) By which I mean,
of course, that we
shall miss you.
Well...
if that's all...
Yeah.
(door opens)
I say, Havers...
It's a bally shame
we won't get to finish
the operation together.
(door closes)
(music playing over video)
NARRATOR (over video):
Which leads to the question:
where next? Mars?
Or even the outer edge
of our solar system?
Only time will tell.
Well, I never.
Anyway, film club...
Yes, now,
I was thinking
9 1/2 Weeks.
Over my already dead
body, sir.
Fine by me.
Guys, guys, look, why don't we
settle this properly, okay?
Quite right.
We'll settle this like men.
Would you care
to step outside, sir?
Indeed, sir.
Guys, you don't
have to do...
Where are you going? I promised
Alison that you wouldn't... Oh.
Oh. (groans)
NARRATOR (over video):
Okay, the moon landings.
Everybody says
it's real,
but what if that's just
what they wanted you
to believe?
Right. You both know the rules.
So we're agreed.
Solve this once and for all.
On three.
One, two, three.
What's that supposed to be?
THOMAS: Pistol.
Thomas, that's...
I always choose pistol.
Oh, yeah, it really worked out
for you last time, didn't it?
(snorts)
There were
circumstances
around my death,
I'll have you know, sir.
It's, uh, rock, paper, scissors,
Thomas. Thought I told you.
No, it's all right,
let's play it his way.
One, two, three.
(clicks tongue)
(imitates machine gun)
What's this now?
AK-47 assault rifle.
Sold 50 crates
of these bad boys
to the Libyans in '83.
You can have
one of these as well.
Well, you don't get two weapons.
(imitates explosion)
Oh, Julian, come on.
And this.
(imitating flamethrower)
You're on fire, mate. Aah!
THOMAS: What?
PAT: Sorry, Mary.
Well, no...
Sorry.
(screams)
Can't feel it.
Nothing happening.
I'm melting.
MIKE:
What should we do with all this?
Maybe just pile it up
over there,
and then we'll deal
with it later.
I think we might just do this.
Oh, great.
How are we gonna
move that?
I think we might
have to break it up
with a big hammer or something.
What? We can't do that.
Can we?
Yeah, why not?
Florence.
Oh, wait.
Can already tell
this isn't good news.
Who's Florence, Kitty?
She was one of my
best friends.
I used to play hide-and-seek
in the garden
with my sister, and I was
so good at hiding
that often she couldn't find me
for a whole day and night.
I once got so hungry, I had to
eat a bit of my purse.
Florence kept me company.
Oh,
so you made a statue
of her?
No, she is a statue.
So we smashing this up or what?
(wailing)
Sorry, one sec, Mike.
No, Kitty, please,
oh, please stop.
Please, um,
we won't, we won't
destroy Florence.
We're just gonna,
uh...
We could move her.
It's a deal.
As long as you play
hide-and-seek with me.
(chuckles)
So we're moving her?
Yeah, sorry.
I think you might be an expert
at this game.
I'm very good at it, yes.
(chuckles) Okay.
Well, you hide first.
(both giggle)
One.
You'll never find me, Alison.
Two.
Three. Okay.
NARRATOR (over video):
And that's why we need
to look seriously
at the grassy knoll.
I mean, look at those angles.
NARRATOR 2:
'Cause Elvis Presley did not
die that day on the toilet.
NARRATOR 3:
That's how we know
the British monarchy
was replaced by weasels.
Mm-hmm.
Hello, Alison.
(Kitty giggling)
Oh...
Oh, you found me.
Oh, I found...
Oh, you're playing, too.
(giggles)
I don't know-- Yes. (laughs)
No one has ever
found me before, ever.
You're so good at this.
Thank you.
Right, your turn
to hide.
I'll count, you hide,
and I'll seek.
Okay.
One.
Oh, it's numbers?
Two.
(muttering)
Three.
Any luck?
(grunts)
She can't move.
(straining)
(both sigh)
(screams)
It's pointless.
(groaning)
Aw...
MIKE:
That was my favorite toe.
ALISON:
You have a favorite toe?
(giggles)
I found you!
(groans)
That was wonderful.
Now you hide and I'll count in.
Yes.
No peeking. (laughs)
Simon says "No peeking."
One.
Two.
Three.
(Mary continues counting)
Oh, so done with this.
No. No.
You know what?
(grunts)
We've cleared loads. I'll get
rid of the garden waste,
and we'll make
the best of it, huh?
Yeah.
Well, next you'll be telling me
gravity doesn't exist.
Well,
you can't see it.
How do you know?
PAT: Alison,
could you explain to Robin that
the moon landings were real?
(overlapping arguing)
MARY:
97.
98.
(Alison gasps)
MARY: 99.
What?
100.
Oh, uh...
(screaming)
What the bally hell
do you think you're playing at?
Alison, get away from there.
Get down. Get Michael out
of the way. It's gonna blow.
It's a bomb!
Mike! Mike!
Get back!
Just get back!
Down!
(distorted):
Get down!
(gasps)
GHOSTS:
Captain?
Oh.
(clears throat)
(screams)
Yeah, maybe you right
about gravity.
Now, I realize that was
an utterly futile gesture,
but I was very much caught up
in the moment. (chuckles)
Wh... What the hell was that?
Now, I was very clear, Alison.
I didn't think you meant
literally explosive.
I thought you meant,
like, it was scandalous.
No.
It was a prototype
limpet mine.
It was so secret
that only I knew about it,
and my second in command
Lieutenant Havers, but
he left me.
I mean, he left for the front,
so, uh, I had to bury it
on my own,
along with the blueprints.
Operation William it was calle.
What?
(car honks)
(gasps)
Oh, that's Martin.
That was the ghost thing?
Yeah.
Maybe next time
tell me if it's a bomb.
I didn't know.
Okay.
I'll stall Clare
and Martin in the house,
and you just... oh, you
just do what you can.
Yeah, actually a very clever
little device.
A cunning timing mechanism
in the housing allowed the
frogmen to exfiltrate safely.
And they... Oh, they've gone,
haven't they?
And this is the
main common room, again.
And we thought that...
It is really nice,
but can we...
Did-did you want
to see the library?
Again?
I'd really love
to see the garden.
Now... Clare, I...
I need you to keep an open mind.
We know that the rest
of the house can be dressed, um,
and we are working on the
garden, believe me.
Um...
(Alison gasps)
Redding weddy.
I love it.
PAT:
Okay,
so, really exciting
presentation tonight, guys.
As promised, Mary
is going to be giving a talk
about her witch trial.
No, sorry, no.
I've had, um,
a-a-a bit of a setback.
Okay. Okay, yeah,
that's understandable, isn't it?
Given the, um...
Sorry.
Yes. So, now seeing
as, uh, we technically
didn't finish
the match,
I've decided
that I'm going to choose
the film tonight.
KITTY:
Is it Love Actually?
I love Love Actually, actually.
9 1/2 Weeks.
The Notebook.
Please don't shout out,
okay? (chuckles)
The film I've chosen
has something for everyone.
Drama, visual poetry,
it's got some of your lot
in it, Robin.
(grunts)
And some
pretty ladies for Julian.
(cheering)
It is, of course,
2001: A Space Odyssey.
Thanks, Pat.
You can be my wingman anytime.
You can be mine.
Uh, it's from
Top Gun.
(Richard Strauss' Also
Sprach Zarathustra playing)
ALISON: Just here.
MIKE: Okay.
(grunts)
Wait, no, that not right.
What?
Earth not round,
it flat.
You what?
It flat.
To our first wedding booking.
Cheers.
Here's to buried secrets.
(music continues)
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org